Umair Qazi

Game Artist - Illustrator - Concept Artist - UI/UX

Digital art specialist with 8+ years of experience in the management of the complete art and design process, from conceptualization to delivery.

Expert at interdepartmental coordination and communication.

Able to stretch the boundaries of digital storytelling to hep stand out from the mainstream school of thought.

Work History

2022-11 -Current

Lead Art Generalist

Quik Games, Lahore, Pakistan

- Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently.
- Contributed in crafting 50+ NFT assets.
- Contributed in crafting base UI wireframes for block-chain meta-verse console game.
- Crafted UI designs for B2B platforms.
- Generated Multiple UX wireframes for SaaS websites/apps.
- Learned new skills and applied to daily tasks to improve efficiency and productivity.
- Met aesthetic and technical criteria to complement design usability and enhance functionality with attractive layouts.

2021-10 -2022-10

Lead Game Designer

Game District, Lahore, Pakistan

- Worked on casual and hyper casual kid's market standard games.
- Successfully crafted multiple end-to-end mobile aames
- Collaborated with artists to achieve appropriate visual style.
- Studied and implemented age specific art style varied in each game.
- Generated concept sketches till final renders for characters, environments and marketing assets.



Contact

Address

Lahore, 54770 PB

Phone

+92-321-4105669

E-mail

umairqaxi@gmail.com

LinkedIn

umair-qazi

Skills

Project Management



Visual Design Creation



UI/UX Design



Concept Art



Digital paint



Character Design



Game art



Illustrations



- Worked on three major products which helped us gain profit of est.\$15k.
- Managed team of employees, overseeing hiring, training and professional growth of employees.

2019-04 - 2D Game Artist

2021-09

2019-08

2017-04

Zoinks Interctive, Lahore, Pakistan

- · Worked on digital assets for 2d games.
- Learned concept art theory and started to implement in design process.
- Worked on kids story book illustrations utilizing adobe photoshop and illustrator.
- Worked on spine animations for game characters.
- Generated NFT collections for clients.
- Worked on editorial cartoons, while learning its unique art style and delivering on time with hundred percent success rate on client's approval.

2017-05 - C.G Artist

The Game Storm Studios, Lahore, Pakistan

- · Created marketing assets for games.
- Collaborated with various artists on multiple 2d and 2.5d games.
- Worked on 100+ in game assets for organization's best selling farming game.
- Learned Digital painting and implemented to deliver beneficial project results.

2016-02 - Junior Game Artist

Creative Distrix, Lahore, Pakistan

- Utilizing adobe photoshop to create icons and logos for mobile games.
- Created 20+ original characters to be implemented in mobile games.
- Created UI designs and in game layouts.
- Worked on in game backgrounds and environments.
- Generated multiple marketing campaigns and assets resulting in visible profit gain.

Education

2011-12 - Bachelor of Arts: Design

Achievements

• NCA 14th Convo-Puppet Prize (2019)

Awarded under the directorship of theatrical society "The Puppeteers"

• Nexskill Skill Development educator award (2018)

Awarded acknowledgement certificate for initiating design course under Nexskill